AMOGH MANNEKOTE

Website · GitHub · LinkedIn · amogh.mannekote@ufl.edu · +1 (352) 562-4114

SUMMARY

I'm a Ph.D. student with a strong software engineering background, currently investigating machine learning and natural language processing based approaches for building dialogue systems for underserved applications (such as negotiation, collaboration, and tutoring). Additionally, I am interested in exploring HCI issues surrounding the development and maintenance of such systems.

EDUCATION

University of Florida
PhD in Computer Science (Dialogue Systems & HCI)

Ramaiah Institute of Technology

B.E. in Computer Science & Engineering

Bengaluru, India 08/2014 - 08/2018

Gainesville, FL

01/2021 - Present

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. [In Progress] Amogh Mannekote, B. Dorr, K.E. Boyer. "Generative Agreement Tracking for Multi-Issue Negotiation Dialogues"
- 2. YRSSDS at SIGDIAL '22 Amogh Mannekote. "Collaborative Dialogue, A Position Paper"
- 3. ACM SIGCSE '22 Amogh Mannekote, M. Celepkolu, A. Galdo, K.E. Boyer, M. Israel, S. Heckman, K. Stephens-Martinez. "Don't Just Paste Your Stacktrace: Shaping Discussion Forums in Introductory CS Courses"

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Florida

Graduate Research Assistant

Gainesville, FL 01/2021 - Present

- · Developed a novel text clustering model to help instructors of undergraduate CS courses analyze student questions on discussion forums (e.g., Piazza) by fine-tuning S-BERT over a dataset of StackOverflow questions. The resulting model outperformed vanilla S-BERT along with various other competitive semantic similarity methods.
- · Designed and implemented a conversational learning partner that would reside within EarSketch. EarSketch is a web-based learning environment that helps high-school learners learn programming through music remixing.

Fractal Analytics & Crux Intelligence

Data Scientist

Bengaluru, India 01/2020 - 11/2020

· Brought down the time-to-release of Crux's platform from one day to a few minutes by implementing an end-to-end evaluation framework for Text-to-SQL Semantic Parsing.

Rasa
Machine Learning Solutions Architect

Berlin, Germany 07/2019 - 11/2019

Machine Learning Solutions Architect

- Developed Conversational AI solutions for enterprise clients across healthcare, automotive, insurance, and retail
 industries.
- · Contributed to Rasa platform development by adding features and maintenance.

Indian Institute of Science (RBCCPS)

Research Assistant

Bengaluru, India 07/2018 - 06/2019

- · Extensively studied and evaluated various state-of-the-art approaches to Visual SLAM with sensor fusion in challenging outdoor environments
- · Improved the accuracy of a extrinsic calibration system that was based on Perspective-n-Point (PnP) by introducing a Grid Search step over the pixel-space of the images

IBM

Intern - Watson Machine Learning Team

Bengaluru, India 04/2018 - 06/2018

· Worked on the serving infrastructure for TensorFlow, Keras, and PyTorch on Watson's ML platform

Stride.AI

Research Intern

Bengaluru, India
02/2017 - 02/2018

- · Designed a multi-turn conversational information-retrieval agent for a Fortune 500 organization to automate searching through their database for employees matching relevant skills
- · Evaluated various approaches such as topic extraction, semantic similarity, text similarity, Doc2Vec, and Siamese networks.

Indian Institute of Science (Dept. of CSA)

Intern at the Game Theory Lab

Bengaluru, India 06/2017 - 08/2017

· Simulated prediction markets using sentiment analysis of news sources

SELECT PROJECTS

MultiWOZ-Gaze Although eye-gaze has been used extensively in NLP, it is underexplored in the context of dialogue corpora. Through this proof-of-concept, we demonstrated the feasibility of using an inexpensive eye-tracker to derive key insights about the MultiWOZ task-oriented dialogue corpus.

Nonechucks An open-source library that provides wrappers around PyTorch DataLoaders to seamlessly handle invalid or unwanted data samples in ML data pipelines (featured on GitHub's Trending Python Repositories).

Rasa-FRAMES A proof-of-concept fork of Rasa Core that supports handling of more than one dialogue "frame" (inspired by the Microsoft FRAMES dataset)

Undergraduate Capstone Improved out-of-distribution generalization of a fully connected neural network by using fine-grained human annotations and a training cost function that penalizes high input gradients in irrelevant regions of the input space.

SKILLS

Programming Python, Java, Javascript, TypeScript, C/C++, Erlang, SQL, IATEX

Machine Learning PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, Matplotlib, WandB

NLP HuggingFace Transformers, spaCy, NLTK, Amazon Lex, Rasa

Infrastructure AWS, GCP, SLURM, Kubernetes, Docker, Git, Bash Web Technologies ReactJS, HTML, Angular, MVC, jQuery, CSS

TALKS & PODCASTS

Guest Speaker on the CS-Ed Podcast

On the use of discussion forums in CS1/2 classrooms [Link]

Building a Chatbot with Rasa

Delivered at Ramaiah Institute of Technology [Link]

ACADEMIC AWARDS & FELLOWSHIPS

Graduate Fellowship, 2022 Awarded by the Dept. of CISE at University of Florida

Student Travel Grant, 2019 For attending CoDS-COMAD 2019

NATURAL LANGUAGES

English (native) · Kannada (native) · Hindi (working)